Finding aid for the Sylvia Plath collection MRBC.MS.00045
Mortimer Rare Book Collection
- Audio visual materials, 1958-2014; 7; 1 linear feet (3 boxes)
  - "In Yeats' house, the death and resurrection of Sylvia Plath", 1982 October 25; 4 items (1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes, mono); cd (copy; 1 cd per cassette side, 65 minutes total); mp3 ) (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Audio recording of Sandra M. Gilbert, "In Yeats' house, the death and resurrection of Sylvia Plath," a program recorded live at Smith College.
  - "The dark repose: a radio biography of Sylvia Plath" recording and advertisement, 1983; 4 items 1 audio cassette (60 minutes); 3 cds (copies) (Box 23, Folder 7)
    This a dramatic program written and directed by Leonard Sanazaro and does not include Sylvia Plath's own voice. With advertisement for broadcast of this recording in Encore! 1983 Oct, page 7.
    Gift (cassette) of Leonard Sanazaro.
    Advertisement gift of Aurelia S. Plath.
  - "Sylvia Plath.": Voices & Visions series, 1988; 1 items 1 VHS videocassette (60 minutes; copy made by donor); VHS copy made by the donor. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Video recording of Sylvia Plath.": Voices & Visions series. National Endowment for the Humanities with label on tape, "Sylvia Plath—on occ. of her death."
    Gift of Perry and Bonnie Norton, 03/30/2007
  - "Five Authors", 1995 June 26; 1 items (1 videocassette ) (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Video recording of "Five Authors," including Sylvia Plath. Double Exposure.
  - CD copy of Alex Beam interview with Ruth Barnhouse about McLean Hospital and typed transcript, 1997 August 9; 2 items (1 cd (copy); 1 transcription (8 pages). ) (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Gift of Alex Beam, 07/31/2000.
    CD is a copy of original cassette in the Ruth Barnhouse Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College.
  - Audio recording of discussion about Sylvia Plath and Ted Hughes on radio program, "The Connection", 1998 January 29; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 24.1, Folder 11)
    Participants in discussion: Christopher Lydon, Peter Davison, and Susan Van Dyne.
    Gift of Eleanor Palmer, 06/14/2001.
  - "Ariel" on "Talk of the Nation", 1998 April 23; 1 items (1 audio cassette (approx. 60 minutes): 2 copies ) (Box 24.1, Folder 12)
    Audio recording of a discussion of Sylvia Plath and her book of poems Ariel with host Ray Suarez, and participants including poet Eavan Boland, artist and Plath's college friend Enid Mark, and various telephone callers. From "Talk of the Nation" radio program (Washington, D.C.: National Public Radio).
    Gift of National Public Radio, 07/10/1998.
  - "Sylvia Plath: The Voice of the Poet" recording and companion book, 1999; 2 items 1 audio cassette (approx. 60 minutes); 1 book (64 pages) (Box 24.1, Folder 13)
    Audio recording of "Sylvia Plath: The Voice of the Poet" (New York: Random House Audio Books, 1999) with companion book containing the complete text of the poems and an essay by J.D. McClatchy. Also with a photocopy of a review (Atlantic Monthly, April 2000) by Wen Stephenson of the first three volumes of "The Voice of the Poet" series, including "Sylvia Plath."
    Gift of J.D. McClatchy, April 1999.
  - "Ted Hughes: Force of Nature", 1999; 1 items 1 videocassette (approx. 120 minutes) (Box 24.1, Folder 14)
    Video recording of "Ted Hughes: Force of Nature" (British Broadcasting Corporation, 1999). Includes some images from the Mortimer Rare Book Collection.
    Gift of BBC, 02/02/1999.
  - "The Ariel Poems: A Return to Form," audio recording and typed transcript, 2004 December 2 (Box 24.1, Folder 14.1)
    CD recording of radio broadcast "The Ariel Poems: A Return to Form," from NPR Morning Edition with typed transcript.
  - "A Poet's Guide to Britain. 'Wuthering Heights' by Sylvia Plath", 2009; 2 items (1 DVD; 1 use copy ) (Box 24.1, Folder 15)
    DVD "A Poet's Guide to Britain. 'Wuthering Heights' by Sylvia Plath" (Prospect Cymru Ltd for BBC Four, ©2009).
    Gift of Melanie Thomas 08/05/2009.
  - "The Spoken Word: Sylvia Plath: the surviving BBC broadcasts", 2010; 1 items 1 cd (73 minutes) (Box 24.1, Folder 16)
    Audio recording of "The Spoken Word: Sylvia Plath: the surviving BBC broadcasts" (London: British Library, 2010).
  - Episode two of BBC "Great Poets in Their Own Words", 2014 June2; 3 items (1 DVD; 2 copies) (Box 24.1, Folder 16.1)
  - "The Poems of Gene Derwood Read by the Poet" with printed booklet and record jacket inscribed "For Sylvia", undated; 1 items 1 sound disc (33 1/3 rpm) (Box 24.1, Folder 17)
    Recorded by the Library of Congress, with an anthology of poets' voices. New Rochelle, NY: Spoken Arts, Inc. With a printed booklet containing full text of the recording. Inscribed on front of record jacket: "For Sylvia."
- Realia, undated; 8; 7 items
  These items owned by Plath include a large plank of elm (used as a writing desk), a typewriter, and painted furniture.
  - Elm plank used as a writing desk by Sylvia Plath, 1 items 7 ft. x 31 in. (Item desk)
  - Cradle, 1 items 16.5 x 10 x 12.5 inches (Box 46)
    Painted by Sylvia Plath, white, with stenciled hearts and vines in red, green, blue, and yellow.
  - Wooden chair (Item chair)
  - Trestle table, 1 items 6 ft. x 25 in. x 30 in. high (Item table)
  - Wicker waste-paper basket, 1 items 10 in. high; 11 in. diameter (Box 47)
  - Typewriter (Item 48)
    Royal, manual portable (serial #Z-1110). According to Aurelia Plath, this was used by Sylvia when she was aged 12-22.
  - Typewriter ribbons, cleaning brush, and cover (Box 48.1)
    Typewriter ribbons (Five Kee Lox inked nylon ribbons, unused, in boxes, with parts of larger Kee Lox ribbon box; one DataTronic ribbon, partly used, in box); typewriter cleaning brush; Royal typewriter plastic cover (sides detached).
- Reviews of Sylvia Plath's work, 1957-1982; 9; .5 linear feet (1 box)
  These reviews are arranged alphabetically by the work reviewed and then, alphabetically by the author of the review (or by title, or publication, if no author listed).
  This series contains a selection of reviews of Plath's published works.
  - Gene Baro review of Ariel from The New York Times Book Review, 1966 June 26; 2 items (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 1)
    Two copies of a review of "Ariel" in "Varied Quintet" in The New York Times Book Review 1966 June 26, pages 10 and 12. The book is reviewd successively with four other books but only the section dealing with Plath is present here. Lane & Stevens 813.
    One copy: Gift of Aurelia S. Plath, 12/03/1983
    Second copy: Gift of Enid Epstein Mark, Smith College class of 1954, 11/1985
  - Review of Ariel from Time, 1966 June 10 (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 2)
    Two copies (one incomplete) of a review of Ariel in "The Blood Jet is Poetry" from Time 1966 June 10, pages 118-120. Lane & Stevens 815.
  - Review of Ariel from Seventeen, 1972 August (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 3)
    Review of Ariel in "Booking-it" from Seventeen. Listed with numerous other "paperbacks to stick in your summer backpack."
  - Irving Feldman review of Ariel from Book Week, 1966 June 19 (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 4)
    Review in "The Religion of One" from Book Week 1966 June 19, page 3. Lane & Stevens 824.
    Gift of Susan Weller Burch, Smith College class of 1955, 05/17/1985.
  - Thomas Lask review of Ariel from The New York Times, 1966 June 8 (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 5)
    Review in "A Kind of Heroism" from The New York Times 1966 June 8, page 45. Review under heading: "Books of the Times." Lane & Stevens 835.
  - Review of Ariel from Newsweek, 1966 June 20 (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 6)
    "Russian Rouletter," review from Newsweek 1966 June 20, page 110. Lane & Stevens 845.
  - Reviews of The Bell Jar, U.K. publication, 1963-1966
    Some of these reviews were provided by Durrant's Press Cuttings, London. Many dates stamped or handwritten on cuttings. Some of the reviews discuss other publications along with The Bell Jar. Some include portraits of Plath or drawings by her. Items listed in Lane & Stevens' Plath bibliography as necessary.
    - "Short List", 1963 January 27; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 1)
      "Short List" by L. Benedict, from Sunday Telegraph 1963 January 27, with cutting information.
    - Photocopy of review from Books and Bookmen, 1963 January (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 1.1)
      Photocopy of review from Books and Bookmen, page 36 and explanatory email from the donor. Photocopy is of an advertisement for The Bell Jar among other "Outstanding Heinemann Books for January."
      Gift of Peter K. Steinberg, 07-21-2009, with his explanatory email.
    - "Transatlantic Englishmen", 1963 January 27; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 2)
      Two copies of a review in Anthony Burgess' "Transatlantic Englishmen" from The Observer, with cutting information. One copy is annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - "New American Fiction: Three Disappointing Novels—But One Good One", 1963 January 31; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 3)
      Review in Rupert Butler's "New American Fiction: Three Disappointing Novels—But One Good One," from Time & Tide 1963 Jan 31, page 34, with cutting information. Lane & Stevens 862.
    - "Are You Our Sort of Person?", 1966 October 19; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 4)
      Review in James Cabourn's "Are You Our Sort of Person?" from The Isis, with cutting information.
    - "Fiction", 1963 January 26; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 5)
      Review in Michael Carr's "Fiction" from Newcastle Journal, with cutting information.
    - "In Short", 1963 February 1; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 6)
      Review in Anne Duchene's "In Short" from The Guardian, with cutting information.
    - "Esther was adept at winning scholarships and prizes", 1963 March 1; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 7)
      Review from Books and Bookmen, incomplete, with cutting information.
    - "Other New Novels: American Surprises", 1963 January 17; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 8)
      Review in Faith Faulconbridge's "Other New Novels: American Surprises" from Glasgow Herald, with cutting information.
    - "Fiction", 1963 January 26; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 9)
      Review in H. Forsyth Hardy's "Fiction" from The Scotsman, with cutting information.
    - "If You are Squeamish Don't Read This Book!", 1963 January 18; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 10)
      Review in Jack House's "If You are Squeamish Don't Read This Book!" from The Evening Times, with cutting information.
    - "In this unusual first novel…", 1963 January 17; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 11)
      Review from Guardian-Journal, with cutting information.
    - "New Novels", 1963 January 31; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 12)
      Review in Laurence Lerner's "New Novels" from The Listener, with cutting information. Lande & Stevens 871.
    - "Newcomer to crime writers' camp is both intelligent and amusing", 1963 January 19; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 13)
      Review in Laurence Meynell's "Newcomer to crime writers' camp is both intelligent and amusing," from Express & Star, with cutting information.
    - "In the Good Old Days", 1963 February 15; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 14)
      Review in Ruby Millar's "In the Good Old Days," from Derbyshire Times, with cutting information.
    - "Miss Victoria Lewis [sic] has written about another girl and another retreat…", 1963 January 26; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 15)
      Review from Sphere, possibly by Vernon Fane, with cutting information.
    - "New Fiction", 1963 January 24; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 16)
      Review from The Times, with cutting information.
    - "New Fiction", 1963 January 31; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 17)
      Review from The Times Weekly Review, with cutting information.
    - "Isolated Case", 1966 September 25; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 18)
      Review by Valarie Pitt from Sunday Telegraph, with cutting information.
    - "The Trouble with Phædra", 1963 February 15; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 19)
      Review by Simon Raven from The Spectator, with cutting information.
    - Photocopy of "Victoria Lucas. The Bell Jar", 1963 March (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 19.1)
      Photocopy of a review by Antonia Sandford from Books and Bookmen 1963 March, page 28. Review of The Bell Jar, signed A.S., among other fiction. Review is with explanatory email from the donor.
      Gift of Peter K. Steinberg, 07-21-2009
    - Copy of "The Disturbed Generation", 1963 January 17; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 20)
      Copy of Maida Stanier's review from Oxford Mail, with cutting information.
    - "Anti-heroes", 1963 January 25; 2 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 21)
      Robert Taubman's review from New Statesman, with cutting information. Two copies, one incomplete. Lane & Stevens 893.
    - "Tyndareus reviews fiction", 1963 January 17; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 22)
      Tyndraeus' review from Time & Tide, with cutting information.
    - "Under the Skin", 1963 January 25; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 23)
      Two copies of a review from The Times Literary Supplement, one copy with cutting information.
    - "Japanese Attitudes", 1963-01-29; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 24)
      Margaret Willy's review from Birmingham Post, with cutting information.
  - Phoebe Adams review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 May (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 1)
    "Short Reviews Books" review from The Atlantic Monthly May 1971, page 224, mounted on Atlantic Monthly stationery. Land & Stevens 854.
  - Lillian Africano review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 May 13; 2 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 2)
    "The Bell Jar," review from The Villager (Greenwich Village, New York), with cutting of date.
  - Photocopy of Ruth Bauerle review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), April 25, probably 1971; 2 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 3)
    Photocopy of "Plath, at Last," review from Cleveland Plain Dealer, page 117.
  - Photocopy of Ghislaine Boulanger review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), probably 1971 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 4)
    Photocopy of "Other Books to Know about," review from Book of the Month Club News, page 5.
  - Edward Butscher review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 February (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 5)
    "On the Late Miss Plath's 'Bell Jar," University Review, page 32.
  - Scott Byrd review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 April 18 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 6)
    "Poet Draws Sad, Baleful Portrait Of A Breakdown," from The Charlotte Observer page 8F.
  - William F. Claire review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), April 13, probably 1971 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 7)
    "A Summer of Her Discontent," from The Washington Post pages C1 and C5.
  - William H. Coe review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 8)
    "Success and Mental Ills of Young Woman," Monterey Peninsula Herald.
  - Dero Coleman review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), probably 1971 May 30; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 9)
    "The Bell Jar", from The Fort Worth Press.
  - College Review Service (Blue Mounds, WI) review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), circa 1971; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 10)
    Review "Recent Fiction" from the College Review Service (Blue Mounds, WI), incomplete.
  - Review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication) from International Socialist Review, 1971 May (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 11)
    "Dilemma of the female choice," review from International Socialist Review pages 29-30, incomplete.
  - Original and photocopy of Helen Dudar review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 September 2 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 12)
    Original and photocopy of the review "From Book to Cult," from the New York Post, pages 3 and 38.
  - Martha Duffy review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 June 21 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 13)
    Two copies of "Lady Lazarus" from Time, pages 87-88. One copy is a clipping and the other is the complete magazine.
  - Wilma R. Ebbitt of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), May 9, probably 1971 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 14)
    Two copies of a review under "Creative Crackup" in Herald Traveler, page 4.
    One copy is a gift of Aurelia S. Plath, 12/03/1983.
  - Julia Aldrich Frados review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), June 20, maybe 1971 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 14.1)
    "The Bell Jar", letter to the editor, New York Times Book Review.
  - Gwen Gaines review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), May 30, probably 1971 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 15)
    Review "Autobiography' Of A Suicide," from The Fresno Bee page D6.
  - Photocopy of Celia Gilbert review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 June 6 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 16)
    Photocopy of "Would the 'Jar' Descend Again?" from San Francisco Examiner & Chronicle pages 41-42.
  - Annie Gottlieb review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 April (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 17)
    "Book Review" from Juris Doctor, page 41.
  - William C. Hamlin review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), June 6, probably 1971 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 18)
    "Fragmentation That Precedes Suicide," from The Kansas City Star, page G3.
  - Elizabeth Hardwick review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 August 12 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 19)
    "On Sylvia Plath" from New York Review pages 3-6. Article is a review of The Bell Jar and Crossing the Water.
  - Harper & Row advertisements for The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 19.1)
    Two clippings of Harper & Row advertisements for The Bell Jar, one is from The New York Times Book Review 1971 April 18.
  - Stanley H. Hill review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 June 2 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 20)
    "What Stanley Hill Read this Week: 'The Bell Jar,'" from The Sun-Bulletin page 4.
  - James Kilroy review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), June 25, probably 1971; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 21)
    "Power and Beauty Mark Novel by Young Suicide," from The Nashville Banner.
  - Original and photocopy of Robert Kirsch review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), probably 1971 April 26; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 22)
    Original and two photocopies of the review "First Novel Also Her Last," from Los Angeles Times. Photocopies are marked marked 4/12 and 5/17.
  - Howard Kissel review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), probably 1971; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 23)
    Article titled "The Bell Jar," from Women's Wear Daily.
  - Photocopy of William Kowinski review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 November 30 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 24)
    Photocopy of review "The Bell Jar" from Boston After Dark, page 44.
  - Betty Leighton review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), probably 1971 June 27; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 25)
    Article titled "Icy Story of Breakdown Real," from Journal & Sentinel (Winston-Salem NC).
  - Photocopy of D.R. Lenson review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), probably 1971 May; 3 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 26)
    Photocopy of article titled "The Bell Jar by Sylvia Plath," from Panache (Princeton, NJ).
  - Original and photocopy of Peggy Lewis review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), June 20, probably 1971; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 27)
    Photocopy and original of article titled ""Tragic Sylvia Plath: She Wanted Out," from The Sunday Times Advertiser (Trenton, NJ).
  - Photocopy of review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication) from Seymour, Wis. Times-Press, 1972 January 13; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 28)
    Photocopy of article titled "Library Corner" from Seymour, Wis. Times-Press.
  - Original and photocopies of Melvin Maddocks review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 April 15 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 29)
    Three copies (2 original and 1 photocopy) of the review titled "A vacuum abhorred" from The Christian Science Monitor, page 13. Lane & Stevens 873.
  - Saul Maloff review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 May 8 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 30)
    Review titled "Waiting for the Voice to Crack" from The New Republic pages 33-35. Lane & Stevens 874.
  - Mitchell J. Morse review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 October (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 31)
    Review titled "Fiction Chronicle" from The Hudson Review pages 525-540. Review of The Bell Jar begins on page 537. Lane & Stevens 875.
  - Photocopy of Howard Moss review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 July 10 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 32)
    Photocopy of review titled "Dying: An Introduction" from The New Yorker pages 73-75. Photocopy includes page 76 and there is a second copy of page 73.
  - Michelle Murray review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), May 31, probably 1971 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 33)
    Original and photocopy of the review "Prose and cons" from National Observer May 31, page 18. Lane & Stevens 877.
  - Review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication) from The Burlington Free Press, 1971 June 30 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 34)
    "New Books" review in The Burlington Free Press, page 12.
  - Review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication) from News-Press, probably 1971 May 5; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 35)
    Review in News-Press (Savannah, GA), in "...in Brief."
  - Review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication) from Newsweek, 1971 April 19 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 36)
    "The Bell Jar," review from Newsweek, 1971 April 19, page 59A. The review is signed G.W.
    Gift of Marcia Brown Stern, 02/16/2012
  - Nichols Christy review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 April 3 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 37)
    "'Bell Jar' sensitive, truthful," review from The State Journal (Lansing, MI), 1971 Apr 3, pages D8-D9.
  - Photocopy of Alleen Pace Nilsen review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1973 November (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 38)
    Photocopy of the review "Death and dying: facts, fiction, folklore," in English Journal 1973 Nov, pages 1187-1189. The Bell Jar is mentioned on page 1188. Land & Stevens 878.
  - Joyce Carol Oates review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), probably 1971 June 6; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 39)
    Review When death called, a lady answered," from Detroit News.
  - Photocopies of J.D. O'Hara review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 April 11 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 40)
    Photocopies of the review "An American dream girl" from Book World (Washington Post?) 1971 Apr 11, page 3. Lane & Stevens 881.
  - Photocopy of T. O'Hara review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 June 1 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 41)
    Two photocopies of the review "The Bell Jar," from Best Sellers 1971 June 1, pages 123-124. Lane & Stevens 882.
  - Photocopy of Domenica Paterno review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication) and Crossing the Water, October 15, probably 1971; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 42)
    Photocopy of the reviews "The Bell Jar" and "Crossing Water" from Library Journal.
  - Catherine Petroski review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 May 9; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 43)
    Review "Insulator, but a cage," from The American Statesman (Austin, TX).
  - Photocopy of Phoebe Pettingill review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 June 28 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 44)
    Photocopy of the review "The Art of Dying," from The New Leader 1971 Jun 28, pages 19-20. Lane & Stevens 885.
  - Photocopy of Elizabeth Pochoda review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), 1971 June 1; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 45)
    Photocopy of the review "The only novel of the dead poet, Sylvia Plath," from Glamour
  - Deborah Powell review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), June 27, probably 1971; 1 pages (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 46)
    Review "When the mind becomes a place of false images" from Detroit Free Press.
  - Review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication) from Publishers' Weekly, 1971 June 7 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 47)
    Review from "Best Sellers," in Publishers' Weekly, page 86.
  - Kit Reed review of The Bell Jar (U.S. publication), June 1, probably 1971 (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 48)
    Review "A frightening apologia," from Middleton Press (Middletown, CT), page 8.